But let's have a look down.
What we are going to cut
You see the plum tree?
It’s blossoming right now
This one, I think, is fine.
Let's cut this one away.
Yeah.
And then very carefully cut this one... Do you have a hand saw?
Yeah. I have a hand saw
And you can use the cutter over there
Yea it’s easier... I’ll do it with the chainsaw
oh no no... i’ll be very careful
Yeah, but this is round.
So you'll damage it anyway.
with the chainsaw I’m more precise than with this
Really? Yea
It’s your tree, haha
Yeah. Oh.
It’s beautiful, how quick it goes
Flowers?
She smells nice!
Yeah.
In fact, you cut a slice
You eat it,
and it's not enough
So you cut another one, and another one
and another one.
Yeah.
Did you grew up in Como?
Oh, really?
I think the most beautiful places in the world
Does it feel like that to you? Or is it just a normal place?
What do you think is one of the most
beautiful places in the world?
Lake Como? Yea
I don't think so.
Nobody thinks so in Italy
It's pretty nice! It's beautiful!
Well I can understand it is gentrified, touristic, etc...
No, I really enjoy the lake in summer especially
and I appreciate where I live, but
but as a local you also see some problems
More in the administration of the city
Also the dog is looking
very interested
How is it?
Good.
Yeah.
I like that we have these flowers
You think you’re gonna be warm sleeping in your hammock?
I'll try. There’s a bit of a draft.
Yea, well
if it's too cold,
I can sleep in the car.
In the seat, or?
No. It's a pretty long car
It's, two meters from,
behind the driver.
So, I have a mattress
Because the blade runs like that.
and if you touch it, like, here
with full throttle...
It will do that.
because the chain goes like that.
Especially if you have...
So that's why you always cut like that
or like that, underneath.
But then the saw wants to go out,
so you have to push a little bit.
You'll feel where the saw wants to go
and you do like half throttle
But this is the danger zone.
You can do it because see chainsaw
guys often like small branches
The artists, you know.
So you can do that.
But usually
like that.
Yeah.
And then this
and it wants to bite in there
And that’s why the dog teeth are there
So they pull the saw in
And you move it a little git
But you can also do like this.
But then the saw wants to come out.
So here this is, sort of, where you have to be careful
Okay.
And your stance needs to be
especially on the hill...
Yeah, I just got this one new
it’s very strong
Couscous!
By Ela.
Does birch burn well?
Yea! It gives a very white fire.
It's a good one ?
Yea it’s fine, but beech is the best
a hard wood, it burns longer
Go!
The big, wild world.
You are free now.
Yea I mean, we need to give them some space
I give them first the food
but give the food outside.
Oh, yeah. You're right.
the brown thing in the puree is ‘noce moscata’
which is in english?
nutmeg
similar as in german
in Dutch as well??
Nootmuskaat
Are you okay with your back?
Do you want any help?
Yea I’m OK. I can use this in the wall.
I wanted to show a walk through the...
the open up pasture,
but there's not so much to see
The weather is turning.
And I'm very allergic to the pollen,
which is the season now, but,
Yeah, we cut a lot of birch here.
We opened it up.
Left, the healthiest trees standing
so they can become wider and kind of thrive.
But mostly this is farmland, so
give space for the cows to graze
when they come in summer
It's talking to Johannes
He came here 11 years ago now, I think.
And he also considered this place.
But in the end,
he found that too much work
He said that this was all free of trees
all open pastures for
cows and goats.
But, you know,
through the years, it's just...
All growing thick with birch, and some beech.
So, Yeah.
Yea we opened it up. A nice batch of firewood
for next years.
Good place for grasses to grow.
And wildflowers.
Nice for a walk.
Have some open space.
So, yeah,
it's really exciting to see, but.
Well, now it's foggy.
There’s a lot of rain coming tomorrow.
And the day after,
I think during
the landscape is really going to transform
because, yeah, things are  blooming.
First, the beech trees
the big forest over there
leaves are coming through very fast.
Now the birch trees are starting
and the other ones as well.
So I think after this weekend it's
gonna green up quite a lot
with all the rain coming.
We had sunny weather
for about three weeks.
It's really beautiful
weather to work outside.
Great help from the guys,
help cutting down and collecting and,
all the branches,
the wood chipper wasn't available
for rent, so I have to do that again
because there's a lot of branches
we need to,
to mulch.
But, yeah.
Good progress.
That's a cherry tree, the one over there.
My dad discovered it
last year, or two years ago.
It doesn't give fruit.
It's just the only one here.
But now it has a bit more light to grow.
Same as that plum tree over there,
which you saw in the beginning.
The white blossom.
It's already disappearing now.
Also doesn't give fruit,
but the blossom is very beautiful.
So now with a little bit more space,
it can can
grow better.
Yeah.
Finishing the walls also.
So that's going to be finished next week
I think another day or two.
And pointing the walls
work on the floor.
And then I can, bring in a bandsaw.
I saw a beautiful bandsaw
on Marketplace, from the 70s.
I think he sent me some videos.
It was working well,
but I have to go and see it
It's far away, it’s from Modena,
so, But I need to have the workshop floor
finished in order to bring in tools.
So first finish that I want to have a bandsaw.
I can work on the rain gutters,
which is going to have a lot of curved wood pieces
the brackets to hold them up.
So that's next.
And work outside goes on as well, depending on the weather